





### education

# **phd** | computer science inria, university of lorraine (fr) 2016-2020 (expected)

- research: design exploration, evolutionary computation, bayesian optimization
- advisors: Jean-Baptiste Mouret, Alexander Asteroth

#### msc | autonomous systems bonn-rhein-sieg university (de) 2012-2019

 research: robotics, evolutionary optimization, neuroevolution, data-efficient optimization

## msc | evolutionary and adaptive systems

university of sussex (uk) 2011-2012

 research: biologically-inspired computation, insect intelligence, neuroevolution, hypernetworks

### bsc | computer science

richmond american international university in london (uk) 2002-2005

• research: species-conserving genetic algorithms for design

### recognition

- Spotlight (NeurIPS) 2019
  Top 2.5% of submissions to
  Advances in Neural Information
  Processing Systems
- Best Paper Award (GECCO) 2018
   Voted best contribution in the
   Complex Systems track of the
   Genetic and Evolutionary
   Computation Conference
- Best Paper Award (GECCO) 2017
   Voted best contribution in the
   Complex Systems track of the
   Genetic and Evolutionary
   Computation Conference
- Best Paper Award (AIAA) 2017
   Awarded by expert panel at AIAA
   Multidisciplinary Analysis and
   Optimization Conference
- Drive-E Studienpreis 2015
  German national award for outstanding student work in electric mobility

#### overview

Nomadic American researcher with eclectic background and research experience spanning evolutionary computation, robotics, and machine learning. Doctoral research concentrated on **integration of evolutionary and machine learning** to solve **real-world design and control** problems. Deep background in biologically-inspired computation, focused on neuroevolution, diversity, and novelty-based approaches. Fascinated by creativity, embodiment, and innateness in machine intelligence.

- → Google Brain internship resulting in a Spotlight presentation at NeurIPS 2019
- → Earned **three best paper awards** over course of PhD at top of field conferences in evolutionary computation and aerodynamics design optimization
- → Background in evolutionary computation, robotics, and machine learning

#### experience

### google brain (tokyo, japan) 2019

| research intern

- developed approach to evolve weight agnostic neural networks (WANN) which perform without explicit weight training (weightagnostic.github.io/) %
- published tool for replication and continuation of WANN experiments
- published general-purpose neuroevolution tool %

#### inria (nancy, france)

| doctoral researcher

2016 - present

- developed approach to combine Bayesian optimization and quality-diversity techniques for design exploration in computationally expensive domains
- published source code of approach (Surrogate-Assisted Illumination) applied to aerodynamic optimization %
- improved data-efficiency of state-of-the-art neuroevolution algorithms by integrating machine learning techniques into the evolutionary process
- analyzed ability of quality-diversity techniques to tackle problems in highly deceptive objective spaces

# bonn-rhein-sieg university (bonn, germany) | research associate 2012 - present

- developed techniques for aerodynamic design optimization and exploration
- evolved neural networks for terrain-aware fuel efficient vehicle control
- designed and taught bachelor's and master's level courses on biologically-inspired and evolutionary computation

## tsinghua international school (beijing, china) | cs department head 2009 - 2011

- created school-wide CS curriculum for new K-12 international school
- taught CS courses, including graphic design, programming, and robotics, to 7th to 12th grade students of mixed language abilities

# various (beijing, china) | bartender, poker pro, restaurant manager 2006 - 2009

Worked as a bartender, sound engineer, and musician at underground rock venue D-22 – paid the bills by playing poker on and offline. Managed the Kro's Nest – an American-style pizza restaurant with an all Chinese staff – and became marketing and IT lead as the first restaurant grew to become a chain of five.

- learned Chinese as a bartender, musician, and restaurant manager
- developed grit, mental resilience, and self-management skills as a poker player
- honed graphic design skills creating ads as marketing lead of a restaurant chain